Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我的名字是马可。
My name is Catherine and today we have a new lesson in our series about interviewing for
我叫凯瑟琳，今天我们要开始一个关于面试技巧的新系列课程。
a new job.
一份新工作。
This is of course at the elementary level.
这当然是初级水平的。
That's right.
没错。
So this is part four of our interview series.
这是我们访谈系列的第四部分。
Remember we are taking a look each week at giving you tips and also the proper language
记住，我们每周都会为你提供一些小贴士，以及正确的语言表达。
for when you have an interview in English.
当你需要用英语面试时。
And on this occasion we're going to talk about our work experience.
在这个场合，我们要聊聊我们的工作经历。
Okay, you remember we talked a little bit about educational experience and educational
好的，你记得我们之前聊过一点关于教育经历和教育方面的事。
background.
背景。
Well today is all about your last couple of jobs.
好的，今天我们要聊的是你最近几份工作的情况。
Alright, so I think we should just listen to the dialogue for the first time and we'll
好的，我觉得我们应该先听一遍对话。
be back in a bit with language takeaway.
马上回来，稍后带来语言要点。
Right Rebecca, now I see that after graduating from university your first job was...
好的，Rebecca，现在我看到你大学毕业后第一份工作是……
For a local paper in York called the York Herald.
为约克当地一家名为《约克先驱报》的报纸工作。
Actually I started with them as an intern.
实际上，我是从实习生开始做起的。
I was really keen on getting some experience in journalism and this seemed like a good
我真的很想获得一些新闻行业的经验，这看起来是个不错的机会。
first step.
第一步。
Certainly.
当然。
And after your internship?
那实习结束后呢？
They seemed impressed and offered me a position as a junior local news reporter.
他们似乎对我印象深刻，给了我一个初级本地新闻记者的职位。
I ended up staying two years there actually.
我实际上在那里待了两年。
I was in charge of the sports news section of the newspaper.
我负责报纸的体育新闻版块。
I really enjoyed it there and it really helped me build my skills.
我真的很喜欢那里，这帮助我提升了技能。
Yes I see, but you decided to leave them in 2006, right?
是的，我明白了，但你决定在2006年离开他们，对吗？
Yes that's right.
是的，没错。
My husband and I moved to London and so I managed to find a position with a national
我和我丈夫搬到了伦敦，所以我设法在一家全国性
newspaper based in London.
报纸找到了职位，这家报纸总部在伦敦。
The London Weekly, right?
《伦敦周刊》，对吗？
Yes.
是的。
In some ways it was a step down from my previous job but it did offer me much better prospects
从某些方面来说，这比我之前的工作降级了，但它确实为我提供了更好的未来前景。
for the future.
未来前景。
Alright we're back so now we've picked out a couple of key words and we're going to take
好了，我们回来了，现在我们挑出了几个关键词，接下来我们要在“语言小贴士”环节看看这些词。
a look at those now on Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
Language Takeaway.
So Marco, a lot of people don't start out as a professional with a job.
那么，马可，很多人并不是一开始就以专业身份从事一份工作的。
They have something else first.
他们先做别的事情。
What is this?
这是什么？
That's right.
没错。
A very popular way to begin your work experience, you become an intern or you work as an intern.
开始你的工作经历的一种非常流行方式，就是成为实习生或以实习生身份工作。
Okay so the name of the job we could say is intern.
好的，所以这个职位的名称我们可以说是实习生。
I'm an intern or he's an intern at my company.
我是实习生，或者他在我公司是实习生。
Exactly.
正是。
So usually interns work at a company.
所以通常实习生在某个公司工作。
Usually they're not paid or if they are it's a very, very little pay and the purpose of
通常他们是没有报酬的，或者如果有，也是非常非常少的报酬，而
an internship or to work as an intern is to gain experience.
实习或作为实习生工作的目的是积累经验。
That's right.
没错。
So it's basically like a study opportunity for a job that you know you want.
所以这基本上是一个学习机会，为你想要的工作做准备。
I could be an intern at a media company and I could learn all about media but it's not
我可以在媒体公司当实习生，学习所有关于媒体的知识，但这并不是
really a full job.
一份真正全职的工作。
Exactly.
正是。
So it's really it serves as an opportunity to maybe continue working at that company
所以它实际上是一个机会，也许可以继续在那家公司工作
in a full time job.
做全职工作。
So you become an intern and the noun or what you are doing is called an internship.
所以你成为实习生，而你所做的事情的名词叫做实习。
So I'm an intern but what I have is an internship.
所以我是实习生，但我拥有的是实习机会。
It's like saying I have a job.
就像说我有工作一样。
I have an internship but I am an intern.
我有实习机会，但我是实习生。
Exactly.
正是。
Alright so we've covered those two words.
好了，我们讲完了这两个词。
Now let's move on to when she's describing her work experience in the York Herald and
现在继续往下，她描述自己在《约克先驱报》的工作经历时，
she described it as a very good first step.
她说那是一个非常不错的第一步。
Okay so a first step you think about your foot, your step, your moving.
好的，所以“第一步”会让你想到脚、步伐、移动。
It means the very first thing you do when you're heading in some direction.
它指的是你朝着某个方向前进时做的第一件事。
Right and professionally I guess your first steps are maybe becoming an intern.
对，从职业角度来说，你的第一步可能是当实习生。
Right or you could say my first step was working in the mail room at this big movie studio
没错，或者你可以说：我的第一步是在这家大电影公司的收发室工作，
but later I became a famous movie producer.
但后来我成了著名的电影制片人。
Exactly so that's kind of like the way that you begin your professional life.
正是这样，所以这有点像你职业生涯的开始方式。
And well then they started talking about the newspapers and actually Rebecca was offered
然后他们开始谈论报纸，实际上丽贝卡得到了
a position as a junior local news reporter.
一个初级本地新闻记者的职位。
Okay so junior means usually lower ranking or not experienced.
好的，所以“初级”通常意味着级别较低或没有经验。
Someone who is just starting out and of course after junior we have senior.
刚起步的人，当然在“初级”之后还有“高级”。
So a senior news reporter is someone who's worked for many many years as a reporter.
所以高级新闻记者是做了很多年记者的人。
Usually I guess a junior news reporter would make less money than a senior news reporter.
通常我觉得初级新闻记者挣的钱比高级新闻记者少。
Exactly you could also say junior executive or senior executive.
没错，你也可以说初级主管或高级主管。
Junior manager.
初级经理。
These are ways of describing length of experience.
这些都是描述经验长短的方式。
And in this case she's junior but what kind of job does she have?
在这个例子里她是初级，但她具体做什么工作呢？
Well she is a news reporter for local issues.
嗯，她是一名负责本地事务的新闻记者。
Okay so she's a local news reporter.
好，所以她是一名本地新闻记者。
Now what exactly does that mean if you're a local news reporter or for local issues?
那么，如果你是一名本地新闻记者，或者报道本地事务，这具体意味着什么？
Well if I live in Chicago and I'm a local news reporter I only write or report the news
嗯，如果我住在芝加哥，并且是一名本地新闻记者，我只撰写或报道新闻，
about Chicago.
关于芝加哥的新闻。
It's a way of describing the things in my area.
这是一种描述我所在地区事务的方式。
So it's the opposite of our next phrase national news reporter.
所以，这与我们下一个短语“全国新闻记者”相反。
Okay so if you are a national news reporter or a national manager of maybe a company then
好，所以如果你是一名全国新闻记者，或者可能是一家公司的全国经理，那么
that means that you oversee things in the whole country.
这意味着你负责整个国家的事务。
That's right so local is my city or my county but in the case of national we're talking
没错，所以“本地”指的是我的城市或我的县，但说到“全国”，我们指的是
about the whole country.
整个国家。
Nation national.
Nation，national。
So national is an adjective.
所以“national”是一个形容词。
But we could even go further than this.
但我们甚至可以更进一步。
What if I am a reporter and I talk about foreign countries?
如果我是一名记者，报道外国事务呢？
I talk about France and South Africa and even Iceland.
我报道法国、南非，甚至冰岛。
Then I guess you would be an international news reporter.
那么我想你会是一名国际新闻记者。
Exactly.
没错。
And I guess also at the executive level you can have an international marketing manager
我想在管理层面上，你也可以有国际营销经理，
right?
对吧？
That's right.
没错。
International marketing manager, national marketing manager.
国际营销经理，全国营销经理。
These are very important ways to divide work to say he is the international manager, he
这些是划分工作的重要方式，用来表明他是国际经理，他
is the national manager.
是全国经理。
This tells you the kind of the size of this person's job.
这告诉你这个人工作的规模大小。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay so now more or less you know how these jobs can be divided junior, senior, national,
好，所以现在你大致了解了这些工作如何划分：初级、高级、全国、
local, etc.
本地等等。
So I think we should go back to the dialogue.
所以我认为我们应该回到对话中。
Let's listen to this dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
让我们再听一遍这段对话，我们一会儿回来。
Alright Rebecca, now I see that after graduating from university your first job was...
好的，Rebecca，现在我注意到你大学毕业后第一份工作是……
For a local paper in York called the York Herald.
在约克一家本地报纸，叫《约克先驱报》。
Actually I started with them as an intern.
实际上，我是以实习生身份开始的。
I was really keen on getting some experience in journalism and this seemed like a good
我当时非常渴望获得一些新闻工作经验，这看起来是一个不错的
first step.
第一步。
Certainly.
当然。
And after your internship?
那实习之后呢？
They seemed impressed and offered me a position as a junior local news reporter.
他们似乎很满意，给了我一个初级本地新闻记者的职位。
I ended up staying two years there actually.
我实际上在那里待了两年。
I was in charge of the sports news section of the newspaper.
我负责报纸的体育新闻版块。
I really enjoyed it there and it really helped me build my skills.
我真的很喜欢那里，这帮助我培养了技能。
Yes I see.
是的，我明白。
But you decided to leave them in 2006, right?
但你决定在2006年离开他们，对吧？
Yes that's right.
是的，没错。
My husband and I moved to London and so I managed to find a position with a national
我和丈夫搬到了伦敦，所以我设法在伦敦的一家全国性
newspaper based in London.
报纸找到了一个职位。
The London Weekly, right?
《伦敦周刊》，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
In some ways it was a step down from my previous job but it did offer me much better prospects
从某些方面来说，这比我之前的工作有所下降，但它确实为我提供了更好的未来前景。
for the future.
未来前景。
Alright so now let's start with a couple of phrases and phrasal verbs on Fluency Builder.
好，现在让我们从“流利度构建”中的几个短语和动词短语开始。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
Okay in today's dialogue we heard a lot of really wonderful phrases Marco.
好的，在今天的对话中，我们听到了很多非常棒的短语，Marco。
Some of them are ways of making your experiences sound better, more professional even.
其中一些是让你的经历听起来更好、甚至更专业的方式。
For example this first one, sorry Rebecca is talking about her first job in York and
例如，第一个，抱歉，Rebecca在谈论她在约克的第一份工作时
she says I was in charge of the sports news section.
说：“我负责体育新闻版块。”
So that phrase, I was in charge of or to be in charge of, what does this describe?
所以这个短语，“I was in charge of”或“to be in charge of”，它描述了什么？
This describes responsibility.
这描述了责任。
Basically she's saying I was responsible for or I had to manage the sports news section.
基本上，她在说她负责或必须管理体育新闻版块。
She's taking credit for this job that was important.
她为这份重要的工作邀功。
Okay so this is a key phrase because this is the typical phrase that you use to describe
好，所以这是一个关键短语，因为这是你用来描述
your responsibilities or to describe what you did in your previous job position or your
你的职责或描述你在之前职位或之前工作中所做事情的典型短语。
previous job.
之前的工作。
So I could ask you when you were in marketing, what were you in charge of?
所以我可以问你，当你在市场营销部门时，你负责什么？
Right and then you say well I was in charge of and then you explain your responsibilities
对，然后你说，嗯，我负责……然后你解释你的职责
or what you did.
或你做了什么。
I was in charge of our national accounts or I was in charge of the local news.
我负责我们的全国账户，或者我负责本地新闻。
Exactly so this is a very simple phrase, just remember it.
没错，所以这是一个非常简单的短语，记住它就行。
I was in charge of and then you can start explaining what were your responsibilities,
我负责……然后你可以开始解释你的职责是什么，
what you did in your previous job.
你在之前工作中做了什么。
Alright moving on now towards the end of that paragraph, Rebecca says that well being in
好的，继续往下，在那段话的结尾，Rebecca说负责体育新闻版块真的很有趣，而且这真的帮助她培养了技能。
charge of the sports news section was really fun and it really helped her build my skills.
这真的帮助我培养了技能。
It really helped me build my skills.
So to build your skills or in this case I build my skills means that I have some skills
所以“培养你的技能”，或者在这种情况下“我培养了技能”，意思是我有一些技能，
but maybe they're not really developed.
但可能还没有完全发展。
Maybe I just finished college, I want more experience.
也许我刚大学毕业，想要更多经验。
Well in that time during my first job I build my skills.
嗯，在那段时间，在我的第一份工作中，我培养了技能。
I become better at writing or having interviews, things like that.
我在写作或采访等方面变得更好了，诸如此类。
Exactly so when you build your skills you kind of improve your abilities or you gain
没错，所以当你培养技能时，你是在提高你的能力或获得
more experience.
更多经验。
Another interesting phrase coming up here when Rebecca talked about moving to London
另一个有趣的短语出现在Rebecca谈到搬到伦敦时。
with her husband she said I managed to find a position with a national newspaper.
她和丈夫说，我设法在一家全国性报纸找到了一份工作。
Okay so I managed to or you could say to manage to do something.
好的，所以我设法，或者你可以说设法做某事。
This is a really interesting phrase because it's another way of saying to be able to
这是一个非常有趣的短语，因为它是一种表达“能够”的另一种方式。
or to succeed at something.
或者成功做成某事。
Okay so don't confuse it with manager or to manage people.
好的，所以不要把它和经理或管理别人混淆。
That is also correct, obviously it exists but to manage to do something is to as you
那也正确，显然它存在，但“设法做某事”就是像你
said to be able to do something.
说的，能够做某事。
Right so for example I was running really late yesterday and I had a ticket for a train
对，比如，我昨天非常晚，我有一张五点钟的火车票。
at five o'clock.
五点钟的火车票。
I thought I would miss the train but I managed to get to the train on time.
我以为我会错过火车，但我设法准时赶上了火车。
That means I was able to get on the train on time.
这意味着我能够准时上火车。
Obviously so you managed to find a job, I managed to get to the train on time, I was
显然，所以你设法找到工作，我设法准时赶上火车，我
able to.
能够做到。
Alright and towards the end Rebecca talked about her job at the London Weekly and she
好的，在对话结尾，Rebecca 谈到了她在《伦敦周刊》的工作，她
described it as a step down from my previous job.
将其描述为比我之前的工作降级了。
Okay is this a good thing or a bad thing Marco?
好的，这是好事还是坏事，Marco？
To be a step down in something is a bad thing.
在某方面降级是坏事。
It's to reduce in level or to decrease.
就是级别降低或减少。
Okay so basically she's saying listen I had this really great job in York and I took a
好的，所以基本上她在说，听着，我在约克有一份很好的工作，我接受了
new job in London and the new job it wasn't as good in many ways because maybe she had
伦敦的一份新工作，而新工作在很多方面没那么好，可能是因为她
less responsibility or maybe it paid less.
责任更少，或者薪水更低。
So this is a way of saying it wasn't as good as my last job.
所以这是一种表达“不如我上一份工作”的方式。
Okay so her new job was a step down from her previous job.
好的，所以她的新工作比她之前的工作降级了。
You could say I think his new girlfriend's a bit of a step down if you know what I mean.
你可以说，我觉得他的新女朋友有点降级，如果你懂我的意思。
So usually you're comparing right?
所以通常你在比较，对吧？
You're making a comparison between something from the past to now.
你在比较过去和现在的东西。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay so a step down.
好的，所以是降级。
Why don't we go back and listen to the dialogue for the very last time and we'll be back to
我们为什么不回去最后一次听对话，我们一会儿再回来
talk to you in a bit.
和你们聊。
Right Rebecca now I see that after graduating from university your first job was...
对，Rebecca，现在我看到你大学毕业后第一份工作是...
For a local paper in York called the York Herald.
在约克一家叫《约克先驱报》的地方报纸。
Actually I started with them as an intern.
实际上，我是以实习生身份开始的。
I was really keen on getting some experience in journalism and this seemed like a good
我当时非常渴望获得一些新闻经验，这看起来是一个不错的
first step.
第一步。
Certainly.
当然。
And after your internship?
实习之后呢？
They seemed impressed and offered me a position as a junior local news reporter.
他们似乎很满意，给了我一个初级本地新闻记者的职位。
I ended up staying two years there actually.
我实际上在那里待了两年。
I was in charge of the sports news section of the newspaper.
我负责报纸的体育新闻版块。
I really enjoyed it there and it really helped me build my skills.
我真的很喜欢那里，它帮助我培养了技能。
Yes I see but you decided to leave them in 2006 right?
是的，我明白，但你决定在2006年离开他们，对吧？
Yes that's right.
是的，没错。
My husband and I moved to London and so I managed to find a position with a national
我和丈夫搬到了伦敦，所以我设法在伦敦的一家全国性
newspaper based in London.
报纸找到了一份工作。
The London Weekly right?
《伦敦周刊》，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
In some ways it was a step down from my previous job but it did offer me much better prospects
从某些方面来说，这比我之前的工作降级了，但它确实为我提供了更好的未来
for the future.
前景。
Alright so talking about internships and interns it seems that usually it's not very exciting
好的，所以谈到实习和实习生，似乎通常成为实习生并不那么令人兴奋，
to become an intern because it ends up that the office people just make you make coffee
因为办公室的人只会让你泡咖啡
or copies and stuff like that.
或复印东西之类的。
You're not really gaining much work experience.
你并没有真正获得很多工作经验。
That is the reputation in the United States for internships.
这就是美国实习的名声。
So basically when you agree to do an internship, sometimes you have to apply to do an internship.
所以基本上，当你同意做实习时，有时你必须申请实习。
It's a very long process.
这是一个很长的过程。
You end up like you say making coffee for people or photocopying reports and this is
你最终就像你说的，给别人泡咖啡或复印报告，这是
really boring work.
非常无聊的工作。
Right.
对。
I think that is the reputation that many places have like you say in the United States but
我认为这是很多地方的名声，就像你说的在美国，但
also I don't know I guess it does seem in a way the only opportunity in order to be
我也不知道，我觉得在某种程度上，这似乎是能够
able to get into an industry or a company.
进入某个行业或公司的唯一机会。
Maybe it's a really good company like I don't know like Procter and Gamble.
也许是一家非常好的公司，比如宝洁。
And how else are you going to be able to get in there with no job experience?
否则，没有工作经验你怎么能进去呢？
Well that's right and a lot of people know that an internship doesn't really give you
嗯，没错，很多人知道实习并不能真正给你
work experience but they still think that it gives you some edge or some advantage when
工作经验，但他们仍然认为这能给你一些优势或好处，当
you're looking for jobs later because if I write down on my resume, we were talking earlier
你以后找工作时，因为如果我在简历上写，我们之前聊过
about resumes, if I write down on my resume that I was an intern at Procter and Gamble,
简历，如果我在简历上写我在宝洁实习过，
wow that's really impressive.
哇，那真的很令人印象深刻。
Right, it looks good.
对，看起来不错。
Alright so this is an interesting topic.
好的，所以这是一个有趣的话题。
Let us know if you were ever an intern.
告诉我们你是否曾经是实习生。
Maybe you started out as an internship or maybe you're doing one now.
也许你从实习开始，或者你现在正在做实习。
Was it better than we say?
它比我们说的更好吗？
Did you do anything else other than making coffee?
除了泡咖啡，你还做了其他事吗？
We really hope so and we look forward to hearing about your experiences.
我们真心希望如此，并期待听到你的经历。
Alright we'll see everyone at EnglishPod.com and until next time.
好的，我们会在 EnglishPod.com 上见大家，下次再见。
Bye.
再见。
EnglishPod is a production of WESO and is not meant to replace proper medical or therapeutic
EnglishPod 是 WESO 制作的节目，不能替代适当的医疗或治疗
treatment.
治疗。